<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Welcome</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://Godnou.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2019-05-11T16:23:49.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://Godnou.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Yanhui</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Physical laws and deep learning</title>
    <link href="http://Godnou.github.io/2019/05/10/PIL/"/>
    <id>http://Godnou.github.io/2019/05/10/PIL/</id>
    <published>2019-05-11T00:00:04.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-11T16:23:49.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Physical laws in our four dimensional world (time + 3D space) are usually mathematically abstracted in the form of partial differential equations. These equations are therefore broadly applied in various boundary value problems(BVPs) arising from natural phenomena or engineering practice, typically, such as wave propagation, heat transfer and elasticity problems. To solve these BVPs, analytical methods (e.g. seperation of variable method, eigenfunction expansion method, Laplacian transformation method) are limited to simple configurations. As the development of computer techniques, numerical methods (e.g. finite element method, finite volume method and finite difference method) show increasingly more powerful capability in solving these BVPs. A natural trend is the fution of the computer techniques and engineering. Thus, numerous engineering software companies (ANSYS, Dassault, Altair, MSC, etc.) emerged during the past seveal decades.</p><p>In recent years, the keyword &quot;data&quot; attracts people's attention due to the highly developed internet and communication techniques. That is the main reason why internet companies (Google, Amazon and many others) were trying to mine the values of the collected data underlying the internet. A trend is that machine learning revives, more precisely speaking &quot;deep learning&quot;. One branch of the hot areas is the design of various neural networks(such as LSTM, CNN, LSTM-CNN), which form the basis of the deep learning techniques and are deemed as universal approximaters. It seems that the &quot;art of fitting&quot;(data modeling) is gradually approaching the &quot;art of reasoning&quot;(mathematical modeling) if dataset for training is large enough. However, it is not true.</p><p>Engineering data are also valuealbe and widely accessible. How can engineering problems in data forms be investigated by deep learning. In general, there are two topics: 1) data &lt;-&gt; physical laws, 2) data &lt;-&gt; solution of BVPs. There have been tremendous researches on these two topics. It is questionalbe that the deep learning techniques can surpass mathematical reasoning and traditional numerical methods. The first question is how large the dataset should be? The second question is the portability of the trained nueral networks, that is to say, once a neural network is trained for a specific BVP, it can not be accommodated to another one. Thus, the deep learning techniques for discovery or solution still cease at a very limited level while the well-documented framework &quot;Tensorflow&quot; seems considerably powerful(e.g. graph calculation scheme and sybolic operators), which anyway opens doors for researches in many different disciplines.</p><p>References can be found here:</p><ol style="list-style-type: decimal"><li><p><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1711.10561" title="Physics Informed Deep Learning (Part I): Data-driven Solutions of Nonlinear Partial Differential Equations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Physics Informed Deep Learning (Part I): Data-driven Solutions of Nonlinear Partial Differential Equations</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1711.10566" title="Physics Informed Deep Learning (Part II): Data-driven Discovery of Nonlinear Partial Differential Equations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Physics Informed Deep Learning (Part II): Data-driven Discovery of Nonlinear Partial Differential Equations</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/324/5923/81" title="Distilling Free-Form Natural Laws from Experimental Data" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Distilling Free-Form Natural Laws from Experimental Data</a></p></li></ol><p>An example about physics informed deep learning is shown as following</p><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/beam_vibration.png"></figure></div><p>Caption: (a) A schematic showing a cantilever beam subject to a tip time-varying force. The displacement data is extracted from the 3 points marked by red cross. (b) showing the geometry parameters, material parameters and the force function. (c) the prediction compared with the exact one.</p><p>The source code and trainng dataset can be found here: script-&gt; <a href="/files/Beam.py">Beam</a> and data-&gt; <a href="/files/data.mat">Data</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Physical laws in our four dimensional world (time + 3D space) are usually mathematically abstracted in the form of partial differential e
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Machine learning" scheme="http://Godnou.github.io/tags/Machine-learning/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>On coding a general user material subroutine</title>
    <link href="http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/30/Hypo_umat/"/>
    <id>http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/30/Hypo_umat/</id>
    <published>2019-05-01T02:02:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-01T23:05:03.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a tutorial, this post shows a simple and extensible user material subroutine (UMAT), where large deformation is considered. For simplicity, the hypoelasticiy is adopted as the material law. The robustness and correctness of the general UMAT is demonstrated in two examples: one is the uniaxial extention test of a single element; the other is the triaxial compression test of a single element.</p><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/hypo.png"></figure></div><p>Caption: (a) uniaxial extension test of a single element (Force v.s. extention). (b) triaxial compression test of a single element (Volume strain v.s. compression). Both examples show the consistent results with the one obtained by the built-in subroutine.</p><p>The source code can be found here: <a href="/files/hypoelasticity.for">Hypoelasticity</a></p><p>Detailed comments are added in the source code for explanation. The framework designed in the source code can be easily applied to other material laws, such as hyperelasticity, plasticity and viscoelasticity.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;As a tutorial, this post shows a simple and extensible user material subroutine (UMAT), where large deformation is considered. For simpli
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="FEM" scheme="http://Godnou.github.io/tags/FEM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Computational multiscale multiphysics analysis of soft composites</title>
    <link href="http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/22/MMASC/"/>
    <id>http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/22/MMASC/</id>
    <published>2019-04-23T02:02:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-01T02:22:29.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Computational multiscale multiphysics analysis of soft composites seems for me to be an interesting topic, where time-dependent material nonlinearity, large deformations, multiphysics coulping and multiscale information passing are accounted for. Out of my personal interest, a finite element package is developt. The project was started in Dec. 2018. It is now still under development. The so-called Nested finite element method(Nested FEM) is used in the calculation. Our calculation capability can demonstrate the effect of complex material heterogeneity ranging from different spatial scales. Herein, we use the dielectric elastomer composites (DECs) as an example(see the following figure).</p><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/NestFEM.png"></figure></div><p>Caption: (a) showing the initial configuration of a bulk DEC brick. (b) showing the deformed configuration of the DEC brick subject to an electric field. (c) showing the heterogenerous structure of the DEC brick, the dielectric permittivities are different in the red regions (inclusion) and the green region (matrix). (d) showing the profile of an intersection. (e) For a single phase material, Nested FEM (inset showing the unit cell) achieves a consistent solution with the analytical one. (f) For a two phase material, the dielectric permittivity of the inclusions is x#(#=1,2,4,6,8) times larger than the one of the matrix (inset showing the unit cell). The limit point, i.e, the largest voltage load, is decreased as the dielectric permittivity of the inclusions increases. Both Nested FEM and direct numerical simulation confirm the same result.</p><p>If one is also interested in this project, you are welcomed to join in developing the package.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Computational multiscale multiphysics analysis of soft composites seems for me to be an interesting topic, where time-dependent material 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="FEM" scheme="http://Godnou.github.io/tags/FEM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Elastomer lattices</title>
    <link href="http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/10/Elastomer%20lattice/"/>
    <id>http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/10/Elastomer lattice/</id>
    <published>2019-04-11T02:50:04.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-11T04:28:04.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first project that I had spent several months to finish in late 2015 when I was pursuing a PhD at the University of Southern California. In order to evaluate the material properties of the architected metamaterials with different lattice structures, they are designed in a CAD software and fabricated by a 3D printer.</p><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/Elastomer_lattice.png"></figure></div><p>A research paper is published based on this. Reference: <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/srep34147" title="Highly-stretchable 3D-architected mechanical metamaterials" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Highly-stretchable 3D-architected mechanical metamaterials</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;The first project that I had spent several months to finish in late 2015 when I was pursuing a PhD at the University of Southern Californ
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="3DPrinting" scheme="http://Godnou.github.io/tags/3DPrinting/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A hierarchical elastomer lattice</title>
    <link href="http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/09/A%20hierarichal%20structure/"/>
    <id>http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/09/A hierarichal structure/</id>
    <published>2019-04-09T14:20:04.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-11T03:55:48.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The pictures below were taken in Apr. 2016. It can be appreciated purely from a aesthetical perspective without any rational pursuit.</p><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/structure.png"></figure></div><p>A research paper is published based on this. Reference: <a href="https://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlehtml/2017/sm/c7sm01435j" title="Stretchable 3D lattice conductors" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stretchable 3D lattice conductors</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;The pictures below were taken in Apr. 2016. It can be appreciated purely from a aesthetical perspective without any rational pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="3DPrinting" scheme="http://Godnou.github.io/tags/3DPrinting/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ferromagnetic elastomer lattices</title>
    <link href="http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/08/Ferromagnetic%20elastomer%20lattice/"/>
    <id>http://Godnou.github.io/2019/04/08/Ferromagnetic elastomer lattice/</id>
    <published>2019-04-09T02:02:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-01T02:15:47.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of my favorite research projects during the time I was studying at the USC. I spent a lot of time and effort on this. The following experimental picture shows that a ferromagnetic elastomer octet-truss lattice is deformed subject to a magnetic field.</p><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/1.png"></figure></div><p>A rough theoretical analysis on the phenomena was given by me in 2016. The PDF file can be found here: <a href="/files/Magnetic_field_Oct_11_2016.pdf">Magnetic Field controlled Buckling and Postbuckling of an Inclined Beam</a></p><p>I left the USC in July 2017. Unfortunately, I did not have time to finish the rest of this research project and many others.</p><p>Anyway, an excellent work based on the ferromagnetic elasomers was finally done by the successors. Reference: <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/adma.201706348" title="Magnetoactive acoustic metamaterials" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Magnetoactive acoustic metamaterials</a> (Big congrats!)</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite research projects during the time I was studying at the USC. I spent a lot of time and effort on this. The fol
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="3DPrinting" scheme="http://Godnou.github.io/tags/3DPrinting/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Permeability for fluid structural interaction</title>
    <link href="http://Godnou.github.io/2018/03/17/Permeability%20for%20fluid%20flow/"/>
    <id>http://Godnou.github.io/2018/03/17/Permeability for fluid flow/</id>
    <published>2018-03-17T18:15:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-10T23:02:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An Octet-truss structure is designed as an representative volume element in a two-scale fluid structural interaction analysis, where the inverse domain is meshed for the fluid field.</p><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/per1.png"></figure></div><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/per2.png"></figure></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;An Octet-truss structure is designed as an representative volume element in a two-scale fluid structural interaction analysis, where the 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="FEM" scheme="http://Godnou.github.io/tags/FEM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thin film buckling</title>
    <link href="http://Godnou.github.io/2018/03/16/Thin%20film%20buckling/"/>
    <id>http://Godnou.github.io/2018/03/16/Thin film buckling/</id>
    <published>2018-03-16T14:02:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-10T22:43:48.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A Film-substrate system is subject to compression, where the film is attached to a soft substrate with complex architecture:</p><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/buckling1.png"></figure></div><p>Buckling modes under different stiffness ratio between the substrate and the thin film:</p><div class="figure"><figure class="figure"><img src="/imag/buckling2.png"></figure></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;A Film-substrate system is subject to compression, where the film is attached to a soft substrate with complex architecture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div cla
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="FEM" scheme="http://Godnou.github.io/tags/FEM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
